지난 이야기
티렐은 골치거립니다
The Tyrells are a problem.
티렐은 스타니스 격퇴를 도왔다
The Tyrells helped us
defeat Stannis Baratheon.
아가씨도 하이가든을 보셔야 해요
You must see Highgarden.
왕비님이 제가 킹스랜딩을
떠나는 걸 허락 안 하실 거에요
I don't think the queen would
let me leave King's Landing.
제가 조프리와 혼인하면
제가 왕비에요
Once I marry Joffrey,
I'll be queen.
아가씨가 로라스
오라버니와 혼인한다면...
And if you were
to marry Loras...
전하께선 빛의 신께
몸을 헌사하셔야 합니다
You must give yourself
to the Lord of Light.
- 내겐 아내가 있다
- 탑에 유페돼있죠
- I have a wife.
- She's shut away in a tower.
아들도 못 낳고
미숙아만 낳았죠
And she's given you no sons,
only stillborns.
사슬에 묶인 왕 시해자에게
내 아들을 잃었소
I lost one son to the Kingslayer,
strangled with a chain.
아드님 일은 조의를 표합니다
I grieve for
your sons, my lord.
조의는 필요없소
복수를 원하오
I don't want your grief.
I want my vengeance.
또 이러면 나머지 손도 자른다
Do that again and I'll
take your other hand.
- 방앗간이 무슨 가치가 있습니까
- 기회를 잡은 거다
- What value was the mill?
- I seized an opportunity.
인질을 잡았어
윌엠, 마틴 라니스터야
We took hostages-- Willem
Lannister, Martyn Lannister.
윌엠과 마틴은 고작 열 네살입니다
Willem and Martyn Lannister
are 14 years old.
난 당신 적이 아니에요
I'm not your enemy.
- 요망한 여잡니다!
- 지하감옥으로 끌고가서 가둬라
- This woman is evil!
- Take him to the dungeon and lock him in a cell.
여자애를 암살하란 말입니까
You want to assassinate a girl?
- 대체 누구의 정보요?
- 조라 모르몬트 경입니다
- Based on whose information?
- Ser Jorah Mormont.
타가리엔의 고문을 맡고있죠
He is serving as advisor
to the Targaryens.
변절자의 정보를
믿으란 말이오?
You bring us the whispers
of a traitor.
베릭 돈다리온?
날 살해할 거면 어서 해라
Beric Dondarrion?
If you mean to murder me,
then bloody well
get on with it.
곧 죽게 될 거다만
살해는 아니다
You'll die soon enough,
but it won't be murder.
명예 전투를 선고한다
I sentence you
to trial by combat.
이제 된 거요?
Is it done, then?
됐다
_
군대는 이 년 거다
거세병!
_
노예상을 죽여라
군인들을 죽여라
_
노예들의 속박을 풀어라
저 년을 죽여!
_
드라카리스
Dracarys.
영자막: honeybunny
한글자막: PsyenceFictionist@gmail.com
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
우리에게 그대의 빛을 비추소서
Lord, cast your light upon us.
빛의 신이시어
우리를 지켜주소서
Lord of Light, defend us.
진실을 보여주소서
Show us the truth.
이 자가 죄인이라면
이 자를 벌하소서
Strike this man down
if he is guilty.
이 자가 무고하다면
이 자에게 힘을 주소서
Give strength to his sword
if he is true.
빛의 신이시어
지혜를 주소서
Lord of Light, give us wisdom.
밤은 어둡고
For the night is dark
공포로 가득하나니
and full of terrors.
밤은 어둡고
공포로 가득하나니
For the night is
dark and full of terrors.
물러나
Get back.
유죄, 유죄, 유죄
Guilty. Guilty. Guilty.
Guilty. Guilty.
Guilty.
유죄, 유죄, 유죄
Guilty. Guilty.
Guilty.
죽여버려!
Kill him!
당신의 종에게
그대의 빛을 비추소서
Lord, cast your light
upon this man, your servant.
죽음과 암흑에서
되돌려 보내 주소서
Bring him back
from death and darkness.
이 자의 불길이
사그라들었나니
His flame has been
extinguished.
불을 지펴주소서
Restore it.
밤은 어둡고
공포로 가득하나니
For the night is
dark and full of terrors.
- 그대의 빛을...
- 아리아, 안 돼!
- Lord, cast...
- Arya, don't!
죽음과 암흑에서
되돌려 보내 주소서
Bring him back
from death and darkness...
안 돼!
No!
이거 놔!
이거 놓으라고!
Let go of me!
Let me go!
저놈들 신은 백정 아들보다
나를 더 좋아하나 보구나
Looks like their god likes me
more than your butcher's boy.
지옥에나 가라!
Burn in hell!
가게 될 거다
He will.
허나 오늘은 아니야
But not today.
오렐 말로는 까마귀들이
장벽을 순찰 중이라는군
Orell says there are crows
patrolling on the Wall.
아는 대로 얘기해라
Tell me what you know.
순찰은 네 명이오
There are four
to a patrol--
공병 둘이 장벽
상태를 확인하고
two builders to check
for structural damage,
수색병 둘이
적을 감시하오
two rangers to watch
for enemies.
순찰 주기는?
How often do these
patrols go out?
위치에 따라 다르오
It varies.
구체적으로 장벽 어디를
노리는지 말해주면 알려주겠소
If I knew where on the Wall we
were heading, I could tell you.
그걸 알고 싶겠지
You'd like to know that.
장벽에는 19개의 성이 있어
There are 19 castles
guarding the Wall.
수비하고 있는
성은 몇 개지?
How many are manned?
세 개요
Three.
확실하냐?
You sure of that?
어느 성이냐?
Which three?
검은 성
Castle Black.
그래, 검은 성
Aye, Castle Black.
검은 성은 이미 알아
Everyone knows Castle Black.
나머진?
Which others?
해안 동부 감시탑
Eastwatch-by-the-Sea
그리고 그림자 탑
and the Shadow Tower.
검은 탑의 수비 인원은?
How many men remain
in Castle Black?
- 천 명
- 거짓말이다
- 1,000.
- Liar.
내가 널 죽이면
네 독수리는 어떻게 되나?
What happens to your eagle
after I kill you?
줄 끊어진 연처럼
날아가 버리나?
Does he drift away like a
kite with his strings cut
아니면 그냥 죽어서
바닥에 떨어지나?
or does he just flop
dead to the ground?
얘는 까마귀 아니야
He's no crow.
너랑 잤다고 이 놈이
우리 일원이 되는 건 아니야
Just 'cause you want him inside
you don't make him one of us.
난 너 안 무섭거든
I'm not afraid of you.
난 네 녀석이 마음에 든다
I like you, boy.
허나 내게 거짓말을 했다간
But if you lie to me,
목구멍으로 내장을 뽑아버릴 거다
I'll pull your guts out
through your throat.
천 명이오
1,000 men.
곧 알게 될 거다
We'll find out soon enough.
내 편 들어줄 필요 없었소
I don't need you to protect me.
편 들어야 할 상황이었어
Of course you do.
딸깍옷이 네 목 따려고
할 때 말려준 게 누구냐?
Who stopped Rattleshirt when he
was about to cut your throat?
만스한테 널
보증해준 게 누구야?
Who vouched for you with Mance?
너 나한테 빚진 거야
It seems you owe me a debt.
- 돌려줘
- 내가 훔쳤는데?
- Give it back.
- Well, I stole it.
이제 내 거야
갖고 싶음 도로 훔치던가
It's mine. If you want
it, come steal it back.
이그리트!
Ygritte!
이그리트! 젠장
Seven hells.
이그리트!
Ygritte!
오렐 말이 맞아?
Is Orell right?
너 아직 까마귀야?
Are you still a crow?
지금 증명해 봐
It's time you proved yourself.
이그리트
Ygritte.
넌 서약을 했지
You swore some vows.
지금 서약을 깨
I want you to break 'em.
날 봐줘
I want you to see me.
내 전부를
All of me.
이러면 안 돼
We shouldn't.
이래야 돼
We should.
안 벗고 뭐해?
Why are you still dressed?
넌 아무 것도 몰라
존 스노우
You know nothing,
Jon Sno--
아까 그 거 있잖아
That thing you did
입으로 해 준거
with your mouth--
남부 영주들은
부인한테 그렇게 해줘?
is that what lords do to
their ladies in the South?
몰라
I don't know.
그냥 거기에
키스하고 싶어서 한 거야
I just wanted to kiss
you there is all.
Hmm.
좋았나 보네
You seemed to like it.
응, 괜찮던데
Aye, I liked it some.
누구한테 배웠어?
Who taught you that?
너 말고는 다른 여자랑
자 본 적 없어
There's been no one else.
Only you.
총각이네
A maid.
너 총각이었구나
You were a maid.
난 밤의 경비대원이었어
I was a man
of the Night's Watch.
넌? 너도 처녀였어?
How about you?
Were you a maid?
어떨 것 같아?
What do you think?
- 어떤 남자였어?
- 그냥 남자애였어
- Who was he?
- Just a boy.
형제들이랑 거래
하러 온 애였지
He came trading
with his brothers.
나 처럼 붉은 머리였어
불길의 입맞춤을 받은 머리
He had red hair like me.
Kissed by fire.
그런데...
But...
힘을 못 쓰더라
he was weak.
너랑은 다르게 말이야
Not like you.
걔가 처음이었어
That was the first one.
그 다음엔 텐이랑 잤고
Then there was this Thenn boy.
공용어를 못 했는데
몸이 완전 맘모스였어
Spoke no Common, but gods,
he was built like a mammoth.
고마운데, 이제
그만 말 해줘도 되겠다
Yeah, thanks.
I think I've heard enough.
돌아가는 게 좋겠어
We'd best get back.
토르문드가...
Tormund--
난 아직 안 끝났어
I'm not done with you yet.
마지막으로 목욕한 게 언제야?
How long's it been
since you had a bath?
돌아가지 말자
Let's not go back.
조금만 더 있자
Let's stay here a while longer.
평생 이 동굴에서
안 나가고 싶어, 존 스노우
I don't ever want to leave
this cave, Jon Snow.
평생
Not ever.
내 돈 돌려줘
I want my gold.
종전 후에 돌려주겠다고
문서에 적어놨잖나
It says it clearly
right there on that note
you'll be repaid in full
when the war is over.
좆 까지마, 도둑놈 새끼들아
Piss on that!
You're nothing but thieves.
우린 무법자야
무법자는 도둑질을 하자
We're outlaws.
Outlaws steal.
목숨 건진 걸 다행으로 알아라
You're lucky
we didn't kill you.
덤벼 보시지, 활잡이
Come try it, archer.
화살을 후장에 박아줄 테니
I'll shove those arrows
up your ass.
풀어주면 안 돼요
살인자고 유죄란 말이에요
You can't let him go. He's a murderer.
He's guilty.
- 신의 관점에선 아닙니다
- 놔주면 안 돼요!
- Not in the eyes of god.
- You can't!
그만! 심판을 하는 건
우리가 아닙니다
Enough! The judgment
isn't ours to make.
가라, 산도르 클레게인
Go in peace, Sandor Clegane.
빛의 신께선
아직 네게 용무가 남으셨다
The Lord of Light
isn't done with you yet.
기병이 온다!
Riders coming through!
The Kingslayer.
내려!
Down!
무릎 꿇어
On your knees.
볼튼 공, 왕 시해자 대령입니다
Lord Bolton, I give you
the Kingslayer.
일으켜 세워라, 로크
Pick him up, Locke.
팔이 없어졌군
You've lost a hand.
아닙니다
여기 있습니다요
No, my lord, he has it here.
- 치워라
- 이놈 아비에게 보낼까요?
- Take this away.
- Send it to his father?
혀 잘리기 싫으면
함부로 혀 놀리지 마라
You'll hold your tongue
unless you want to lose it.
숙녀분 풀어줘라
죄송하오, 아가씨
Cut her free.
Apologies, my lady.
이제 내가 책임지겠소
You're under my protection now.
감사합니다
Thank you, my lord.
손님께 방을 마련해 드려라
Find suitable rooms
for our guests.
나중에 얘기하지
We'll speak later.
볼튼 공
Lord Bolton.
수도에서 전언 없었소?
Is there word from the capital?
못 들었소?
You haven't heard?
스타니스 바라티언이
킹스랜딩을 공격했소
Stannis Baratheon laid siege
to King's Landing.
블랙워터 만으로
함대를 몰고 왔소
Sailed into Blackwater Bay.
수 천 병력으로
성문을 타격했소
Stormed the gates
with thousands of men.
귀경 누이는...
And your sister...
이걸 어찌 말 한다?
How can I put this?
당신 누이는...
Your sister...
멀쩡히 잘 살아있소
is alive and well.
당신 부친의 군대가 승리했소
Your father's forces prevailed.
제이미 경 상태가 안 좋구나
Ser Jaime isn't well.
카이번에게 데려가
Take him to Qyburn.
- 난 죽는 건가?
- 아닙니다
- Will I die?
- No.
감염이 퍼졌습니다
The corruption has spread.
잘라내야 겠군요
I fear it must be cut away.
팔 전체를 자르는 게
가장 안전한 방법입니다
The safest course would be
to take the whole arm off.
그럼 자네가 죽는다
Then you'll die.
자넨 문관이 아니잖나
You're no maester.
목걸이는 어디있지?
Where's your chain?
시타텔에서 압수했습니다
The Citadel stripped me of it.
제가 하던 실험을 들켰는데
They found some
of my experiments
좀 과한 실험이었거든요
too bold.
팔꿈치 아래로만
자르도록 하죠
I can leave your upper arm,
make the cut at your elbow.
오른 손 없어도
네 놈은 죽일 수 있다
I don't need my right hand
to kill you.
그렇다면 썩어가는
살을 제거하고
I can take away
the rotting flesh
끓인 포도주로 감염을
태워 없애도록 하죠
and try and burn out
the corruption
- with boiling wine.
- Mmm.
운이 좋다면
그걸로 될 겁니다
With any luck,
that will suffice.
양귀비 탄 우유를
드셔야 할 겁니다
You'll need milk of the poppy.
- 양귀비는 됐다
- 고통스러울 겁니다
- No milk of the poppy.
- There will be pain.
- 비명을 지르도록 하지
- 상당한 고통입니다
- I'll scream.
- Quite a bit of pain.
비명을 더 크게 지르지
I'll scream loudly.
배일리쉬 공
Lord Baelish.
왕비님
Your Grace.
부탁 하나 하고 싶군요
I wonder if I might
ask you for a favor.
말씀만 하십시오
Of course, Your Grace.
아무래도 티렐가는
왕실에 어울리지 않는다 봅니다
I have reason to believe
that House Tyrell
do not hold the crown's
best interests at heart.
그렇군요. 타이윈 공도
동의하시는 겁니까?
I see. And have you shared these
suspicions with Lord Tywin?
아버님은 합리적인 분이죠
입증된 사실만 따지십니다
My father's a practical man.
He appreciates facts.
개인적으로 입증된
사실은 장애가 되기도 하더군요
Myself, I often
find them a hindrance.
게다가 아버님은 가문의
조력자를 우대하시지요
And he appreciates those who aid
his family, as you well know.
가문을 돕지 않은 이를
달가워하지 않으시는 만큼
He's almost as generous
to those who help us
가문을 도와준 이를
귀하게 여기시죠
as he is unpleasant
towards those who don't.
귀공은 티렐과
좋은 관계를 유지하고 계시죠
You have a good working
relationship with the Tyrells.
수도를 떠나기 전에
방법을 찾아 주시겠어요?
I thought you might look into it
before you leave the capital.
- 노력해 보겠습니다
- 고맙군요
- I shall do my best.
- Thank you.
아리아 스타크를 찾을 때보다
더 노력하시리라 믿어도 될까요?
And your best will prove better than
when I asked you to locate Arya Stark?
약속드리죠
I assure you that it will.
됐다, 이 녀석아
여기가 무슨 주점이냐
Gods, boy, that's enough.
We're not in a tavern.
- 죄송합니다
- 사과는 됐다
- Pardon, my lady.
- No need to speak.
무화과 있으면
좀 갖다 주렴
Are there any figs?
Fetch some.
오후엔 늘
무화과를 먹는다오
I always take figs
midafternoon.
소화가 잘 되거든
They help move the bowels.
날 찾은 이유가 뭐요?
To what do I owe this summons?
와 주셔서 감사합니다
Thank you for seeing me,
my lady.
몇 가지 재정 문제를
논하고자 합니다
I had hoped we might discuss
a few financial matters.
재정 문제를 논하자고
내가 힘들게 여기까지 온 거요?
I climbed all those steps to
discuss financial matters?
왕실 혼인식 문젭니다
It's the royal wedding.
부인께서 혼인식
준비 중이시라 들었습니다만?
I'm told you had a hand
in planning it.
그야 당연하죠
Naturally.
상당히 우려되는 문제더군요
It's shaping up to be
a very involved affair.
지나치게 사치스럽지
않냐는 말이 있습니다
The word extravagant
has been used.
왕실 혼인식이 사치스럽지 않으면
무슨 소용이겠소?
What good
is the word extravagant
if it can't be used
to describe a royal wedding?
- 그렇긴 하군요
- 그렇죠
- I understand that.
- Good.
허나 제가 재무관이다보니
왕실 경비를 담당해야 하거든요
But, as Master of Coin,
it falls upon me
to calculate the cost
for the crown.
지금으로선 너무 큰 경비입니다
As of now, it's a huge expense.
그래서요?
And?
지금은 전시 상황입니다, 올레나 부인
And we're at war, Lady Olenna.
어머, 깜빡 잊었네
Oh, I'd nearly forgotten.
네, 보급 물자를 충당하려면...
Yes, and maintaining
supply lines--
어쩌다 그걸 깜빡했을까나
I can't think
how it slipped my mind.
어디보자, 티렐가에서
보병 1만2천 명을 지웠했죠?
What is it, 12,000 infantrymen
the Tyrell family has supplied?
창기병 1천8백 명에
1,800 mounted lances.
지원군 2천 명까지요
2,000 in support.
이 도시가 겨울을 날 수 있는
지원물자도 줬고요
Provisions so this city
might survive the winter.
밀 2천만 말이요
A million bushels of wheat.
보리, 귀리, 호밀도
각 1천만 말 줬고요
Half a million bushels each
of barley, oats, and rye.
소 2만 마리에
20,000 head of cattle.
양 5만 마리도요
50,000 sheep.
나한테 전시 경비에 대해
가르치려 들 필요 없어요
You don't have to lecture me
about wartime expenses.
이미 잘 알고 있으니까
I'm quite familiar with them.
왕국의 보전을 위해 기여해 주신
점에 대해 깊은 감사 드립니다
And we are so grateful
for your contributions
which are necessary for the
preservation of the realm.
왕실 혼인식도 마찬가지요
As is a royal wedding.
백성들은 음식에만
굶주린 게 아니외다
The people are hungry
for more than just food.
현실에서 눈을 돌릴
거리을 원하고 있어요
They crave distractions.
우리가 그런 거리를 제공하지 않으면
백성들이 스스로 만들어 낼 거요
And if we don't provide them,
they'll create their own.
백성들이 만들어낸 거리는
필경 우리가 사지 절단되는 결과겠죠
And their distractions
are likely to end
with us being torn to pieces.
왕실 혼인식이 훨씬
안전한 방법입니다
A royal wedding is much safer.
- 안 그런가요?
- 그렇군요
- Wouldn't you say?
- I would.
전통적으로 왕가에서
치러야 할 대가이기도 하죠
And traditionally paid for
by the royal family.
귀공이 주정뱅이에
뻔뻔하고 방탕하다 들었소
I was told you were
drunk, impertinent,
and thoroughly debauched.
이제 보니 장부나 끼고 따져대는
분이라 어찌나 실망스러운지
You can imagine
my disappointment
at finding nothing but a
browbeaten bookkeeper.
무화과 따러
볼란티스까지 갔다왔냐?
Where did you go
for them, Volantis?
- 부인...
- 뭐, 좋아요
- My lady--
- Oh, very well.
티렐가에서 부담을
지지 않겠다는 말은 아니요
I won't have it said
that House Tyrell
refuses to play its part.
경비는 반 씩 부담하고
We'll pay for half the expenses
혼인식은 계획대로 합시다
and the celebrations
will go on as planned.
- 이거면 충분하죠?
- 충분합니다. 감사하군요
- Is that sufficient?
- Quite sufficient. Thank you.
좋아요, 그럼 이제 된 거죠
잘 계쇼
Very good, then. That's settled.
Good day.
줘 봐라
Give me that.
뭐 하냐?
What are you doing?
베릭 공 갑옷 고치는데?
Just mending
Lord Beric's armor.
뭐 하러?
Why?
형제단 대장장이로 일 할 거야
I'm going to stay on
and smith for the Brotherhood.
너 미쳤어?
Have you lost your mind?
라니스터 군한테 잡히면
대장장이라고 살려줄 것 같아?
When the Lannisters find this place,
you think they'll spare the smiths?
네가 만든 투구로
네 머릴 박살낼 걸
They'll cave your head in
with your own helmet.
형제단 아니어도 라니스터는
원래 날 죽이려고 했어
The Lannisters wanted to kill me long
before I joined the Brotherhood.
이럴 필요 없잖아
You don't have to do this.
하고 싶어서 하는 거야
I want to.
이 사람들은 인재가 필요해
They need good men.
롭 오빠도 인재 필요해
내일 떠나자
Robb needs good men, too.
We're leaving tomorrow.
- 그러면...
- 뭐? 그 사람을 섬기라고?
- And then you--
- What? Serve him?
난 평생 누구를 섬기고 살았어
I've served men my entire life.
킹스랜딩에선
모트 사부를 섬겼는데
I served Master Mott
at King's Landing
사부가 날 경비대에 팔아넘겼지
and he sold me to the Watch.
하렌할에서
타이윈 공을 섬길 땐
I served Lord Tywin
at Harrenhal,
매일 언제 고문당하고
죽지 않을까 노심초사였어
wondering every day if I'd
get tortured or killed.
누굴 섬기는 건 그만 둘래
I'm done serving.
방금 베릭 공을 섬긴다며
You just said you were
serving Lord Beric.
베릭 공은 형제단이
선택한 지도자야
He may be their leader,
but they chose him.
이 사람들은 형제야
가족이라고
These men are brothers.
They're a family.
난 평생 가족이 없었어
I've never had a family.
내가 가족이 돼 줄게
I can be your family.
넌 내 가족이 될 수 없어
You wouldn't be my family.
넌 귀족 아가씨니까
You'd be "my lady."
윌엠
Willem.
윌엠!
Willem!
- 구해주러 온 건가요?
- 라니스터 새끼! 끌고 가!
- Is this a rescue?
- Lannister filth! Take him!
이러지 마세요
전 그냥 종자에요
Please, I didn't do anything.
I'm just a squire.
제발요
Please--
들여 보내시오
Bring them in.
이게 전부요?
Is that all of them?
비무장인 종자 둘을
살해하는 데 다섯 명이 필요하던가?
It took five of you to
murder two unarmed squires?
살해가 아닙니다
Not murder, Your Grace.
복수입니다
Vengeance.
복수?
Vengeance?
귀공 아들을 죽인 건
이 애들이 아니오
Those boys didn't
kill your sons.
난 하리온이 전사하는 걸
봤고, 토헨은...
I saw Harrion die on the
battlefield and Torrhen--
왕 시해자에게
교살당했습니다
Was strangled
by the Kingslayer.
- 이 애들은 같은 핏줄이오
- 어린 애들 아니오!
- They were his kin.
- They were boys!
이 애들을 보시오
Look at them.
전하 어머님더러
보라 하십시오
Tell your mother
to look at them.
전하 어머님도 똑같이
책임이 있으니까요
She killed them as much as I.
내 어머님은 이 일과 관련없소
My mother had nothing
to do with this.
이건 귀공의 반역이오
This was your treason.
적을 풀어주는게 반역이지
It's treason
to free your enemies.
전쟁에선 적을 죽이는 거다
In war, you kill your enemies.
아버지가 안 가르쳐 주더냐?
Did your father
not teach you that, boy?
그냥 두어라
Leave him.
그래
Aye.
전하께 할 말 하게 두어라
Leave me to the king.
날 풀어주기 전에
잔소리 하시려는 모양이니까
He wants to give me a scolding
before he sets me free.
반역을 그렇게
처벌하는 분이시니까
That's how he deals
with treason.
북부의 왕이시어
Our King in the North.
아니, 차라리
Or should I call him
북부를 말아먹은
왕이라 불러야 하나?
the King Who Lost the North?
카스타크 공을
지하감옥으로 모셔라
Escort Lord Karstark
to the dungeon.
나머진 교수형이다
Hang the rest.
자비를 베푸십시오!
전 아무도 안 죽였습니다
Mercy, sire!
I didn't kill anyone.
전 망만 봤습니다
I only watched for the guards.
저 녀석은 망만 봤단다
This one was only the watcher.
동료들이 죽는 모습을 보게
마지막에 목 매달아라
Hang him last so he can
watch the others die.
제발 이러지 마십시오!
시켜서 한 겁니다!
Please! Please, no.
They made me do it!
시켜서 한 겁니다!
They made me!
이 소문이 리버런 밖으로
나가선 안 됩니다
Word of this
can't leave Riverrun.
이 애들은
타이윈 라니스터의 조카고
They were Tywin
Lannister's nephews.
라니스터는 빚을 갚습니다
The Lannisters pay their debts.
이 건을 계속 들먹일 겁니다
They never stop
talking about it.
나더러 살인자도 모자라서
거짓말쟁이가 되라는 거요?
Would you make me a liar
as well as a murderer?
난 거짓말 안 할 거요
It wouldn't be lying.
매장하고 전쟁이 끝날 때까지
비밀에 부칩시다
We will bury them
and remain silent
until the war is done.
내 출신 성분이 무엇이든 간에
I'm not fighting for justice
내 부관들을 정의롭게
심판하지 못 한다면
if I don't serve justice
to murderers in my ranks,
정의를 위해 싸운다 할 수 없지
no matter how highborn.
사형시킬 거요
He has to die.
카스타크가는 북부인이다
The Karstarks are Northmen.
영주를 죽이면
결코 가만있지 않을 거야
They won't forgive
the killing of their lord.
어머님 말씀이 맞습니다
Your mother's right.
사형시키시면 카스타크가는
전하를 버릴 겁니다
If you do this, the
Karstarks will abandon you.
당신이 애들을 치료했소
You tended to their wounds.
당신이 밥을 먹였소
그런데 애들이 죽었소
You brought them supper.
Now they're dead.
이 전쟁을 치르는 동안
더 많은 아이들이 죽을 거에요
And more boys will keep dying
until this war is over.
카스타크 병사가 있어야
전쟁을 끝낼 수 있어요
You need Karstark men
to end it.
살려 주거라
포로로 데리고 있어라
Spare his life.
Keep him as a hostage.
포로로요
A hostage.
카스타크가에게 충성을 지킨다면
영주는 무사할 거라 하십시오
Tell the Karstarks that as
long as they remain loyal,
he will not be harmed.
나도 너와 마찬가지로
최초인의 피가 흐른다
The blood of the First Men
flows through my veins
as much as yours, boy.
난 네 아버지와 함께
미친 왕과 싸웠다
I fought the Mad King
for your father.
난 널 위해 조프리와 싸웠다
I fought Joffrey for you.
우리는 동족이다
We are kin--
스타크와 카스타크
Stark and Karstark.
그렇다고 해서 당신의
반역이 없어지진 않소
That didn't stop you
from betraying me.
처벌을 면할 수도 없소
And it won't save you now.
누가 처벌을 면하겠다나
I don't want it to save me.
평생 네 녀석을 괴롭히는
기억으로 남길 바라는 거다
I want it to haunt you
to the end of your days.
무릎 꿇으시오
Kneel, my lord.
리카드 카스타크
Rickard Karstark,
카홀드의 영주
Lord of Karhold,
신들과 백성들 앞에서
나 그대에게 사형을 고하노라
here in sight of gods and
men, I sentence you to die.
마지막 남길 말 있소?
Would you speak a final word?
빨리 죽이기나 하고
저주나 받아라
Kill me and be cursed.
넌 내 왕이 아니야
You are no king of mine.
조프리
Joffrey.
서세이
Cersei.
일린 페인
Ilyn Payne.
메린
Ser Meryn.
사냥개
The Hound.
날 어떻게 할 거야?
What are you
going to do with me?
동이 트면 리버런으로 갈 겁니다
At first light
we'll ride for Riverrun.
오라버님이 거기 계십니다
Your brother's there now.
우리 대의에 도움을 준다면
He'll make a contribution
to our cause
아가씨를 보내 줄 겁니다
and you can go home.
날 인질로 팔아넘기는 거네
I'm a hostage
and you're selling me.
그런 식으로 생각하지 마시죠
Don't think of it that way.
- 하지만 그런 식 맞잖아
- 맞죠
- But it is that way.
- It is.
- 하지만 아니기도 합니다
- 아닌 점 보다 맞는 점이 많잖아
- And it isn't.
- More is than isn't.
베릭은 아가씨 아버님을
무척 존경했답니다
Beric admired your father
a great deal, you know.
베릭도 아가씨의
몸값 받는 걸 반대했죠
He wanted to refuse
your ransom altogether.
- 당신은 왜 반대 안 하는데?
- 돈이 필요하니까요
- So why don't you?
- We need the gold.
나 때문에 무섭냐
Do I frighten you, child?
아니
No.
나한테 화났구나
You're angry with me.
그럴만 하지
And I don't blame you.
허나 그 녀석을
보내는 게 옳은 일이었다
But letting him go
was the right thing.
그놈이 산 원한보다
살려줘야 할 이유가 더 컸어
I have more reason than most
to want him hanged.
- 사냥개한테 죽은 줄 알았는데
- 죽었지
- I thought he killed you.
- He did.
그럼 어떻게...?
But how...?
소로스...
Thoros...
날 몇 번이나 되살렸소?
how many times
have you brought me back?
공을 살린 건 빛의 신입니다
It's the Lord of Light
brings you back.
전 그저 그분의 말을 전하는
운 좋은 주정뱅이일 뿐이죠
I'm just the lucky drunk
who says the words.
- 몇 번이지?
- 다섯 번일 겁니다
- How many times?
- Five, I think.
아니, 이제 여섯 번이구나
No, this makes six.
여섯 번
Six.
처음은 거산에게 당하셨죠
There was the first time--
the Mountain.
보여주세요
Show her.
창에 가슴을 관통당했죠
Lance right through the chest.
그 다음엔 배에 칼을 맞았고
Then I was stabbed
in the belly.
그 다음엔 등에 화살 맞았고
Then it was an arrow
in the back.
그건 도끼 맞은 자국이고요
And that axe in the side.
그리고 라니스터한테 잡혀서
반역죄로 처형당했지
Then the Lannisters caught me
and executed me for treason.
목 매달려서 죽었나,
눈에 단검 박혀서 죽었나?
Was it a hanging
or a dagger in the eye?
둘 다죠
그 새끼들이 결정을 못 내렸죠
Both.
Fuckers couldn't decide.
사냥개한테 죽은 게
여섯 번째고요
And the Hound makes six.
클레게인에게 두 번 당했군
Second time I've been
killed by a Clegane.
이제 아실만 하잖아요
You'd think you'd learn.
갈 수록 더 힘들어 질 겁니다
It's not getting
any easier, you know.
아네
I know.
되 살아날 때마다
Every time I come back,
뭔가 조금씩 잃어버려
I'm a bit less.
자신의 일부가 사라져
Pieces of you get chipped away.
머리가 잘린 사람도
살릴 수 있어?
Could you bring back
a man without a head?
여섯 번 까진 됐고
한 번만이라도
Not six times.
Just once.
그렇게는 안 될 것 같구나
I don't think it works
that way, child.
네드 스타크는 의인이었어
He was a good man, Ned Stark.
지금은 다른 세상에서
안식을 찾았을 거다
He's at rest now, somewhere.
그분을 위해서라면
목숨도 불사했을 거야
I would never wish
my life upon him.
기꺼이
I would.
당신은 살아있잖아
You're alive.
제게 당신의 빛을 비춰주소서
Lord, cast your light upon me.
어둠 속에서 절 지켜 주소서
Protect me in the darkness.
저의 죄를 불태우소서
Burn away my sins.
당신을 섬기게 해주소서
Help me serve you.
저를 당신의 의지대로 사용하소서
Use me as you will.
밤은 어둡고
For the night is dark
공포로 가득하나니
and full of terrors.
전하가 오시길
밤낯으로 빌었어요
I have prayed day and night
for you to come to me.
부인
My lady.
진작 오고 싶었소만
I meant to come sooner.
- 전쟁 문제로...
- 바쁘신 건 알아요
- The battle--
- I know of your troubles, my king.
멜리산드레에게 모두 들었어요
The Lady Melisandre
has told me everything.
그래, 그럴 거요
Yes, of course.
절망하지 마세요
전하의 왕권은 진실하니
You mustn't despair.
Your claim is true.
- 승리하실 겁니다
- 나도 그리 믿었소
- You will be victorious.
- I believed that once.
전하는 신의 용사에요
You are the one god's champion
제가 아는 최고의 남자고요
and the finest man
I've ever known.
셀리스
Selyse.
난 성스러운 서약을 어겼소
I've broken a sacred vow.
난 죄인이오
I've sinned.
- 아니에요
- 난 당신에게 죄를 졌소
- No.
- I've wronged you.
- 당신을 수치스럽게 했소
- 전하는 신의 위업을 하신 거에요
- I have shamed you.
- You're doing god's work.
당신은 모르오
You don't understand.
붉은 여인은...
The Red Woman--
멜리산드레는...
the Lady Melisandre--
알아요, 자기
I know, Stannis.
멜리산드레가
모두 말 해 줬어요
The Lady Melisandre
has told me everything.
빛의 신을 섬기기 위해
한 일은 죄가 될 수 없어요
No act done in service
of the Lord of Light
can ever be a sin.
멜리산드레에게
그 얘기를 듣고
When she told me,
전 기뻐서 눈물을 흘렸어요
I wept with joy.
우리 아기들
Oh, my sweet boys.
피터, 토마드
Petyr, Tommard,
에드릭
Edric.
신께 매일 감사드려요
I thank god every day
멜리산드레를 보내주셔서
for bringing Melisandre to us.
멜리산드레가 전하의
아들을 낳아줬잖아요
She gave you a son.
전...
I gave you...
- 아무 것도 못 드렸는데
- 그렇지 않소
- nothing.
- That's not true.
그 애도 보러 오신 건가요?
So you've come
to see her as well?
그럴 필요 없어요
There is no need.
지금 일에 집중하셔야죠
You must keep away
from such distractions.
그 애는 내 딸이오
She's my daughter.
딸을 보고 싶소
I want to see her.
전하는 왕이십니다
You are a king.
제 허락은 필요 없으시죠
You don't need my permission.
♪ 바다 속에선♪
♪ Under the sea ♪
♪ 난 알아요♪
♪ I know, I know ♪
♪ 오, 오, 오♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ 새들은 비늘이 달렸고♪
♪ The birds have scales ♪
♪ 물고기에겐 날개가 있죠♪
♪ And the fish take wing ♪
♪ 난 알아요♪
♪ I know, I know ♪
♪ 오, 오, 오♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh... ♪
시린
Shireen.
아버지!
Father!
그 새 많이 자랐구나
You've grown
since I last saw you.
전쟁을 하셨다면서요
Mother said you fought
in a battle.
이기셨나요?
Did you win?
아니
No.
양파 기사님도
함께 돌아오셨나요?
Did the Onion Knight
come back with you?
그랬지
He did.
용맹하게 싸웠다
He fought bravely.
저 보러 안 오셨는데
He hasn't come to visit me.
수도에서 선물 사오신댔는데
He said he'd bring me back a
present from the capital.
양파 기사는 안 올거다
He won't be visiting, child.
왜요? 기사님은 제 친군데
Why not?
He's my friend.
보세요
Look.
저한테 이거 만들어 주셨어요
He made this for me.
어머니한텐 말하지 마세요
But don't tell Mother
I have it.
비밀이니까요
It's a secret.
어머니는 양파 기사님을 싫어해요
Mother doesn't like
the Onion Knight.
다보스 경은 반역자다
Ser Davos is a traitor.
죄를 지어서
지하감옥에 있다
He's rotting in a dungeon
cell for his crime.
그 사람은 잊어라
Best forget him.
뭘 그리 박박 문지르나
피부 다 벗겨지겠어
Not so hard.
You'll scrub the skin off.
여긴 왜 온 거요?
What are you doing here?
목욕 하러
I need a bath.
이 넝마 좀 벗겨다오
Help me out of these rags.
이제 나가봐
Now get out.
탕은 또 있잖소
There's another tub.
난 여기가 좋은데
This one suits me fine.
걱정 마, 관심 없으니까
Don't worry.
I'm not interested.
내가 기절하거든
나 좀 꺼내주라고
If I faint, pull me out.
욕탕에서 죽는 최초의
라니스터가 될 생각은 없으니까
I don't intend to be the first
Lannister to die in a bathtub.
당신이 죽든 말든
내가 무슨 상관이오?
Why should I care how you die?
서약을 하지 않았나?
You swore a solemn vow,
remember?
날 몸 멀쩡히 킹스랜딩으로
데려가야 하잖아
You're supposed to get me to
King's Landing in one piece.
일이 잘 안 풀리지?
Not going so well, is it?
자네가 지키던 렌리가
죽은 것도 무리는 아니야
No wonder Renly died
with you guarding him.
괜한 말을 했군
미안하네
That was unworthy.
Forgive me.
자넨 누구보다도
날 잘 지켜줬어
You protected me
better than most--
- 조롱하지 마시오
- 사과하는 거요
- Don't you mock me.
- I'm apologizing.
싸움은 지긋지긋해
I'm sick of fighting.
휴전합시다
Let's call a truce.
휴전을 하려면
신뢰가 있어야지
You need trust to have a truce.
난 당신을 신뢰해
I trust you.
바로 그거야
바로 그 표정이지
There it is.
There's the look.
17년 동안 매일
봐오던 얼굴이야
I've seen it for 17 years
on face after face.
다들 날 경멸하지
You all despise me.
왕 시해자
Kingslayer.
서약을 어긴 자
Oathbreaker.
명예가 없는 자
A man without honor.
지옥 기름 아나?
You've heard of wildfire?
당연히 알지
Of course.
미친 왕은 지옥 기름에 미쳤었지
The Mad King
was obsessed with it.
사람들이 타 죽는 모습을 좋아했어
He loved to watch people burn,
피부가 타들어가고
물집이 생기고
the way their skin
blackened and blistered
녹아서 뼈만 남는 모습을
and melted off their bones.
마음에 안드는
영주는 태워 죽였지
He burned lords he didn't like.
거역하는 수관도
태워 죽였어
He burned Hands
who disobeyed him.
반발하는 이는
모두 태워 죽였어
He burned anyone
who was against him.
이내 왕국 절반이
왕에게 반발하게 됐지
Before long, half the
country was against him.
아리스는 모두가
반역자라고 생각했어
Aerys saw traitors everywhere.
그래서 화염술사에게 도시
전체에 지옥기름을 배치 시켰지
So he had his pyromancer
place caches of wildfire
all over the city--
베일러 신전 밑에
beneath the Sept of Baelor
플리 빈민가에
and the slums of Flea Bottom.
집에, 마굿간에, 주점에
Under houses, stables, taverns.
심지어는 붉은 성채 밑에도
Even beneath
the Red Keep itself.
결국
Finally,
파멸의 날이 다가왔어
the day of reckoning came.
로버트 바라티언이
트라이덴트에서 승리하고
Robert Baratheon
marched on the capital
after his victory
at the Trident.
수도로 진군했지
하지만 내 아버님이
라니스터 전군을 대동하고
But my father arrived first
수도에 먼저 도착해서
with the whole Lannister
army at his back,
반란군에게 수도를
지키겠다 약속하셨지
promising to defend the city
against the rebels.
허나 아버님은 내가 잘 알아
I knew my father
better than that.
지는 쪽을 선택할 분이 아니지
He's never been one
to pick the losing side.
난 미친 왕에게
수 없이 말했어
I told the Mad King as much.
평화적으로 투항하자 했어
I urged him
to surrender peacefully.
허나 왕은 내 말을 듣지 않았어
But the king didn't
listen to me.
바리스의 경고도 듣지 않았어
He didn't listen to Varys
who tried to warn him.
그런데 파이셀 대문관의
말은 들었지
But he did listen
to Grand Maester Pycelle,
그 늙은 노친네 새끼 말을
that grey, sunken cunt.
라니스터는 믿을 수 있다고 했지
"You can trust
the Lannisters," he said.
라니스터는 늘 왕실의
진정한 동반자였다고
"The Lannisters
have always been
true friends
of the crown."
그래서 도시 문을 열었고
So we opened the gates
아버님은 도시를 장악해버렸지
and my father sacked the city.
난 재차 왕에게 가서
Once again, I came to the king,
투항하라 애원했어
begging him to surrender.
왕이 하는 말이...
He told me to...
아버님의 머리를 가져오라더군
bring him my father's head.
그러더니
Then he...
화염술사에게 말했어
turned to his pyromancer.
모조리 태워버려라
"Burn them all," he said.
놈들의 집을 모조리 태워라
"Burn them in their homes.
놈들의 침대도 모조리 태워라
Burn them
in their beds."
자네가 그렇게
좋아라 하는 렌리가
Tell me, if your precious Renly
자네더러 아버지를 죽이고
commanded you to kill
your own father
수천 명의 백성들을
여자와 아이들까지
and stand by while
thousands of men,
산 채로 태워 죽이라 하면
women, and children
burned alive,
할 수 있겠나?
would you have done it?
그래도 서약을 지킬 건가?
Would you have
kept your oath then?
난 먼저 화염술사를 죽였어
First, I killed the pyromancer.
다음엔 왕이 도망가려 할 때
And then when the king
turned to flee,
등에 내 칼을 박았지
I drove my sword into his back.
모조리 불태우라고 했어
"Burn them all,"
he kept saying.
모조리 불태우라고
"Burn them all."
왕은 자기가 죽을 거라
생각 안 했을 거야
I don't think
he expected to die.
왕은 아마...
He-- he meant to...
다 같이 불 타버린 다음에
burn with the rest of us
다시 부활해서
and rise again,
용으로 다시 태어나
reborn as a dragon
적들을 잿더미로
만들 줄 알았던 거지
to turn his enemies to ash.
행여 그런 일이 있을까
내가 목을 그어버렸지
I slit his throat to make sure
that didn't happen.
그때 네드 스타크가
날 발견했어
That's where Ned Stark
found me.
그게 사실이라면...
If this is true...
왜 아무에게도 말 안 했소?
why didn't you tell anyone?
왜 스타크 공에게 말 안 했소?
Why didn't you tell Lord Stark?
스타크?
Stark?
자네는
You think
그 명예로운 네드 스타크가
the honorable Ned Stark
내 말을 들으려고
했을 것 같나?
wanted to hear my side?
날 본 순간 이미
He judged me guilty
날 죄인이라 낙인 찍었어
the moment he set eyes on me.
대체 늑대가 무슨 권리로
By what right does the wolf
사자를 심판한단 말인가!
judge the lion?
- 무슨 권리로!
- 도와주시오!
- By what right?
- Help! Help!
왕 시해자가!
The Kingslayer!
제이미야
Jaime.
내 이름은 제이미야
My name is Jaime.
양파 기사님
Onion Knight.
Ser Onion Knight.
공주님? 여긴 대체
왜 오셨습니까?
Princess? Gods, what
are you doing here?
- 쉿, 버트가 깨겠어요
- 버트요?
- Shh, you'll wake Bert.
- Bert?
뚱보요
오늘 경비 담당이에요
He's the fat one.
He's on guard duty tonight.
술 좋아하고
잠이 많아요
He likes to drink wine
and sleep a lot.
공주님 방으로 가세요
여기 오시면 안 됩니다
Go back to your room. You're
not supposed to be here.
- 아버님이 아시면...
- 기사님이 반역자래요
- If your father knew--
- He said you were a traitor.
정말이에요?
Are you?
그래요
I am, child.
공주님 아버님이신
왕의 명을 거역했습니다
I disobeyed my king,
your father,
지금 그 대가를
치르는 중이고요
and now I'm paying the price.
상관 없어요
기사님은 제 친구에요
I don't care.
You're my friend.
여기 있으면
엄청 지루할테죠
You must get bored down here.
읽을 책을 가져왔어요
I brought you
something to read.
애곤과 용 이야기에요
It's about Aegon
and his dragons.
애곤은 여기 살았대요
그거 아셨어요?
Aegon used to live here.
Did you know that?
- 이 성도 타가리엔이 지은 거고요
- 압니다
- And the Targaryens built this castle.
- Aye.
- 사실이죠
- 책은 망토에 숨기면 되요
- So they did.
- You can hide the book under your cloak.
재미있는 책이에요
또 가져다 드릴게요
It's a good one.
I'll bring you more.
고맙습니다, 공주님
좋은 책이긴 합니다만
Thank you, my lady.
I'm sure it's a fine book,
저한테 주시는 건 낭빕니다
but it's wasted on me.
받아요
전 또 있어요
Take it.
I have more.
공주님, 전 글을 못 읽습니다
My lady, I can't read
the words.
못 읽어요?
You can't?
제가 가르쳐 드릴게요
버트 근무 때마다 올 게요
I'll teach you. I'll come when
Bert's on duty and teach you.
- 아닙니다. 안 됩니다
- 쉬워요, 재미있을 거에요
- No. No. No.
- It's easy. It'll be fun.
- 가세요, 이러시면...
- 왜 안 돼요?
- Go. We can't.
- Why not?
뭘 어쩌겠어요?
감옥에 가두나?
What will they do,
lock us in cells?
어디서 부터 시작해야
할 지 모르겠네요
I wouldn't know where to start.
처음부터요
At the beginning.
이 단어는 애곤이에요
This word is Aegon.
A, E, G가 합쳐지면요
When you see A, E, and G
together like that,
에그라고 발음해요
it sounds like egg.
이 책의 정식 제목은
And the title of the whole book
정복자 애곤의
is "An History
of Aegon the Conqueror
웨스테로스 정복기에요
and His Conquest
of Westeros."
꽤 피곤한 공성전이었군요
It was a
bitch of a siege.
파이크를 처음
돌파한 게 자네였던가?
Mm, you were first through
the breach at Pyke?
두 번 쨉니다
소로스의 미르가 단신으로
The second. Thoros of
Myr went in alone,
불타는 검을 들고
뛰어들어갔죠
waving that
flaming sword of his.
미르의 소로스
그 미친 놈 말인가
Thoros of Myr.
Bloody madman.
그 전투 후에 로버트가
작위를 내렸나?
Robert knighted you
after the battle?
평생에 가장
자랑스런 순간이었죠
Proudest moment of my life.
땅에 무릎을 꿇고
왕의 검이 어깨에 올라오고
One knee in the dust, the
king's sword on my shoulder,
왕의 말을 듣던 순간이요
listening to the words.
전사의 이름답게
용맹히 살 것을 명한다
"In the name of the Warrior,
I charge you to be brave."
정작 전 빨리 오줌싸고
싶다는 생각 뿐이었습니다
All I could think of
was how badly I had to piss.
전신 철갑을
16시간동안 입고
In full plate
metal for 16 hours.
전쟁이 끝날 때까지
그런 일은 없었는데
Never occurred to me
till the fighting was over.
최초로 왕의 신발에
오줌싼 기사가 될 뻔했습니다
I was very nearly the first man
knighted to piss on the king's boots.
로버트라면 웃어 넘겼을 거야
Robert would have laughed.
좋은 사람이었어
뛰어난 전사였지
He was a good man,
a great warrior.
형편없는 왕이었고
And a terrible king.
형편없는 왕을 지키느라
반평생을 낭비했네
I burned away my years
fighting for terrible kings.
- 서약 하셨잖습니까
- 했지
- You swore an oath.
- Yes.
명예로운 이는
서약을 지켜야지
And a man of honor
keeps his vows,
설령 주정뱅이나
미치광이를 섬기더라도
even if he's serving
a drunk or a lunatic.
다만 죽기 전에
평생에 단 한번
Just once in my life
before it's over,
긍지를 가지고
믿음으로 섬긴다는 것이
I want to know what it's
like to serve with pride,
무엇인지 알고 싶었네
to fight for someone
I believe in.
전하를 믿나?
Do you believe in her?
진심으로 믿습니다
With all my heart.
이 자들이냐?
These are the ones?
네, 장교들입니다
Yes, khaleesi.
The officers.
너희들은 이런 삶을
선택하지 않았다
_
허나 그대들은 이제 자유인이니
스스로 선택해야 한다
_
그대들 중에서
지도자를 선출했나?
_
투구를 벗어라
소인 영광입니다
_
이름이 무어냐
회색 벌레입니다
_
회색 벌레라?
거세병은 거세할 때
이름을 새로 받습니다
All Unsullied boys
are given new names
when they are cut--
회색 벌레, 붉은 벼룩, 검은 쥐
Grey Worm, Red Flea, Black Rat.
자신들의 존재를
일깨우는 이름입니다
Names that remind them
what they are--
기생충임을요
vermin.
이 시간부로 자신의
이름은 스스로 정한다
_
전우들에게도 그대로 전해라
노예 이름은 버려라
_
부모님이 지어주신 이름이나
새로 지은 이름을 써라
_
자랑스러운 이름을 써라
회색 벌레는 자랑스러운 이름입니다
복이 따르는 이름입니다
_
소인이 태어날 때
받은 이름은 저주 받았습니다
_
그 이름으로 살다가
노예가 됐습니다
_
하지만 회색 벌레란 이름으로 살다
폭풍의 딸 대너리스를 만나 자유가 됐습니다
_
로버트 왕은
전하를 죽이려 했습니다
King Robert
wanted her dead.
당연히 죽이려 했지
Of course he wanted her dead.
타가리엔이잖나
최후의 타가리엔
She's a Targaryen.
The last Targaryen.
의회에서 로버트를
설득 시킬 사람은 없었겠죠
I suppose no one on the small
council could speak sense to him.
- 난 의회에 참석 안 했네
- 그렇습니까?
- I didn't sit on the small council.
- No?
전통적으로 국왕 친위대의
사령관이라면...
Doesn't the Lord Commander of
the Kingsguard traditionally--
전통적으로 그렇지만
난 로버트가 반란군일 때
Traditionally, yes,
but I killed a dozen
로버트의 친구를
수십 명 죽였네
of Robert's friends
during his rebellion.
미친 왕을 위해 싸운 내게
정사 조언을 받고 싶어하지 않았지
He didn't want advice
on how to govern
from a man who had fought
for the Mad King.
전 그닥 신경 안 씁니다만
Can't say I minded much.
정치는 늘 싫었네
I always hated the politics.
저라도 그랬을 겁니다
Yeah, I imagine I would, too.
몇 시간이고 세상을 어떻게 뒷통수치고
배반할지나 노닥거리니
Hours spent jabbering
about backstabbings
- and betrayals the world over.
- Mm-hmm.
하지만 전하도
칠왕국을 통치하려면
Still, she'll have
to wade through that muck
그 똥물을 거쳐가야 하네
if she wants to rule
the Seven Kingdoms.
충실한 조언자를 얻게 될 걸세
She'll have good men
around her to advise her,
노련한 이들로
men with experience.
마음에 두시는 분이 있습니까?
Which men do you have in mind?
이런 말 해서 미안하네만
Forgive me, Ser Jorah,
for what I'm about to say,
지난 몇 년간 웨스테로스에서
자넨 악명이 높았다네
but your reputation in Westeros
has suffered over the years.
그럴만 하니까요
It suffered for a reason.
전 노예 매매를 했습니다
I sold men into slavery.
우리가 고국으로
돌아갔을 때
I don't know if your
presence by her side
자네 존재는 전하 명분에
도움이 되지 않을 걸세
will help our cause
when we go home.
전하 명분에요?
Our cause?
죄송합니다만 경께서
로버트에게 굽신댈 때
Forgive me, Ser
Barristan, but I was busy
defending the khaleesi against
King Robert's assassins
전 전하가 암살당하지 않게
막느라 바빴습니다만
while you were still
bowing to the man.
우리 둘다 전하가
통치하시길 원하지 않나?
We both want her to rule.
Am I wrong?
경은 합류하신지
고작 며칠 안 되셨잖습니까
You only joined us
a few days ago.
경의 저의를 모르겠습니다만
I can't speak
to your intentions.
자네가 진정 충신이라면
If we're truly
her loyal servants,
해야 할 일은
반드시 해야 하네
we will do whatever
needs to be done,
대가나 우리 자존심이
문제가 아닐세
no matter the cost,
no matter our pride.
경은 여기선 사령관이 아닙니다
You're not Lord Commander here.
경도 유배자일 뿐이죠
You're just another exile.
제게 명령을 하는 건
전하 뿐입니다
And I take my orders
from the queen.
- 침소로 오세요
- 당신 말이 맞소
- Come to bed.
- You were right.
카스타크는 떠났소
The Karstarks are gone.
거진 병력의 절반이오
Almost half our forces.
타이윈 라니스터는 우릴
와해시킬 방법을 알 거요
Tywin Lannister knows what he
needs to do to make us unravel.
아무 것도 안 하는 거지
Nothing.
기다리기만 하면 되니
Only wait.
그렇게 두지 마세요
Don't let him.
내가 뭘 할 수 있겠소?
What can I do?
킹스랜딩을
공격이라도 해야 하오?
Attack King's Landing?
그야말로 놈이 바라는 바지
There's nothing
he'd like better.
하루만에 궤멸당할 거요
He'd crush us in a day.
북부로 가면 되죠
We could ride north.
그레이조이에게 빼앗긴
고향을 되찾는 거에요
Take your land back
from the Greyjoys.
- 겨울이 끝나길 기다리세요
- 겨울은 5년이 갈 수도 있소
- Wait out the winter.
- Winter could last five years.
기수들이 고향에 돌아가서
Once my bannermen
are home again,
가족들과 함께
불가에 앉아
sitting by the fire,
surrounded by their families,
등 따시고 배불러지면
다시는 남군하지 않을 거요
warm and safe, they'll
never ride south again.
내가 영주들을 소집했을 땐
명분과 대의가 있었소
When I gathered
my lords together,
we had a purpose, a mission.
이제 우린 말다툼하는
어린애 무리나 다름없소
Now we're like a band
of bickering children.
새로운 동기를 주세요
Give them a new purpose.
어떤?
What?
모르겠네요
Oh, I don't know.
전 윈터펠이
어딘지도 몰라요
I don't even know
where Winterfell is.
여기요
Here.
우린 여기고
저긴 킹스랜딩이요
And we're here.
King's Landing--
뭔가요?
What is it?
놈들을 야전으로
끌어들일 순 없소
I can't force them
to meet us in the field
놈들의 가장 강한
주둔지를 공격할 수도 없소
and I can't attack them
where they're strongest,
허나 약한 곳을
공격할 순 있지
but I can attack them
where they're not.
카스털리 록이
어디 도망갈 순 없소
And Casterly Rock
can't run away.
놈들의 고향을 빼앗겠소
I'm going to take
their home away from them.
할 수 있나요?
Can you do it?
고향으로 복귀한카스타크군을
대체할 병력이 필요하오
I need men to replace the
Karstarks who marched home.
현재 라니스터 편이 아닌 군대를
가진 이는 왕국에 단 한 명 뿐이오
There is only one person
in this kingdom
with that kind of army who hasn't
already sided with the Lannisters.
딸을 나와 혼인시키려 했던 자
The man whose daughter
I was supposed to marry--
왈더 프레이요
Walder Frey.
대단한 검사시네요
He's such a splendid fighter.
혹시 대체 언제쯤...
Do you have any idea
when we might...
조프리와 혼인하는대로
물밑 작업을 시작할 거에요
I'll plant the seed as soon
as Joffrey and I are married.
금방 진행 될 거에요
It should grow quickly.
조프리는 절
보내주지 않을 거에요
Joffrey won't let me leave.
절 여기 둬야할
이유가 많으니까요
He's got too many reasons
to keep me here.
보내줘야 할 이유는
하나 뿐이죠
And only one to let you go.
그래야 제가
좋아할 테니까요
Because it will please me.
종자!
Squire!
잘 싸우셨습니다
Well fought, ser.
뭘 이정도 가지고
자넨 누군가?
That was no fight.
I don't know you.
올리버입니다
도와드리죠
Olyver, if it please you.
경께 걸맞는 상대와
대련하시는 걸 보고싶군요
I should like to see you spar
with a proper partner, ser.
어떻게 알았지?
How did you know?
뭘요?
Know what?
내가 원했다는 걸
That I wanted to.
경...
My lord...
난 조만간 혼인할 건데
I'll have you know
I'm to be married soon
내가 원해서 하는 건 아니야
and even my intended
hasn't the slightest notion.
경험 상 보통 다들 그렇더군요
They rarely do,
in my experience.
자넨 경험이 꽤나 많을 거야?
You have a good deal
of experience, do you?
남편들과는요
With the husbands.
오래 걸리지 않았군요
That didn't take long.
그 정도면 오래 걸린 거죠
Well, it took long enough.
꽃의 기사가 약혼
중인 것 같더군요
It seems our Knight of Flowers
is engaged to be wed.
그런가요?
Is he?
그렇다면...
And...
그 운 좋은 아가씨는 누구죠?
who's the lucky girl?
저 배가 세상에서
가장 큰 배는 아니야
She may not be
the grandest ship in the world
가장 빠르지도 않고
or the fastest,
하지만 내 배지
but she's mine.
늘 배를 가지고 싶었단다
I've always wanted a ship.
이젠 함대를 가지고 싶구나
Now I want a dozen.
- 참 이상하지?
- 뭐가요?
- Strange, isn't it?
- What is?
뭘 원하든간에
It doesn't matter what we want,
일단 손에 넣으면
once we get it,
다른 걸 원한다는게
then we want something else.
머리 매무새가
달라졌구나
Your hair is different.
그래요?
Is it?
마저리 아가씨가
그런 머리를 하지
Lady Margaery
wears it that way.
이런 머리는 많이들 해요
Many ladies wear it this way.
좋은 소식이 있단다
I have good news.
곧 도시를 떠날 거야
I'll be leaving the city soon.
아직도 절
데려가고 싶으세요?
You still want me
to come with you?
내 의사가 문제가 아니야
It's not a question
of what I want.
네[ 의사가 문제지
It's what you want.
고향에 가고 싶지?
You want to go home, don't you?
물론이죠
더할나위 없어요
Of course.
More than anything.
하지만 기다리는 게
좋을 지도 모르겠어요
But maybe it would
be better to wait.
아무래도 너무
위험하지 않나 싶어요
I've been thinking
how dangerous it would be.
저 뿐만 아니라 공도요
Not just for me, but for you.
이렇게 친절히 해주시는데
You've been so kind.
행여 무슨 일 생기시면
속상해서 어떡해요
I'd feel terrible if
anything happened to you.
이거 너무 감동적이구나
I can't tell you
how touched I am
내 안녕을 걱정해 주다니
by your concern for my welfare.
내가 네 친구라는 걸 알아주렴
I hope you know that
I'm your friend, Sansa.
진정한 친구라는 걸
Your true friend.
그럼요, 베일리쉬 공
I do, Lord Baelish.
- 피터라고 불러
- 피터
- Petyr.
여기 남고 싶다면
If you wish to stay,
얼마든지 남으렴
then of course you will stay.
내가 돌아오면
다시 얘기하자꾸나
We'll speak again
when I return.
늦었구나
You're late.
누난 왜 있는 겁니까
What's she doing here?
이 애하고도
관련이 있는 일이다
Our business concerns her, too.
앉거라
Sit.
좋은 소식을 알려드리자면
You'll be pleased to learn
제가 올레나 티렐과
말 몇 마디 한 것 만으로
that after one conversation
with Olenna Tyrell,
왕실의 혼인 비용
수백만을 절감했습니다
I've saved the crown
hundreds of thousands
on this wedding.
그건 지금 문제가 아니다
Never mind that now.
지금은 중요한 사안이 있다
We have something
important to discuss.
전 재무관입니다
경비 절감은 중요한 거죠
I'm Master of Coin.
Saving money is important.
웃지 마
Stop that.
안 그래도 불편하구만
You're making me uncomfortable.
네 누이가 이르길
네 새 친구 티렐이
Your sister has learned that
your new friends the Tyrells
산사를 로라스 경과 혼인시킬
음모를 꾸미는 중이라더구나
are plotting to marry
Sansa Stark to Ser Loras.
잘 됐네요
Very well.
예쁜 아가씨니까요
She's a lovely girl.
로라스가 좋아하는
부위는 없지만
Missing some of Loras'
favorite bits,
둘이 잘 해낼 겁니다
but I'm sure they'll make do.
- 농담은 적당히 하거라
- 더 재밌게 할 수도 있는데
- Your jokes are not appreciated.
- It wasn't my best, but--
티렐을 왕실에 받아줬더니
이런 식으로 은혜를 갚다니
I bring them into the royal fold
and this is how they repay me,
내 수중에 있는 북부의
열쇠를 빼앗으려 들어
by trying to steal the key to
the North out from under me.
산사가 북부의 열쇤가요?
Sansa is the key to the North?
오라비가 있던 걸로 기억하는데
I seem to remember
she has an older brother.
카스타크가 귀향했다
The Karstarks
have marched home.
젊은 늑대는 병력 반을 잃었다
이제 오래 못 버틴다
The young wolf has lost half his army.
His days are numbered.
테온 그레이조이가 남동생
둘을 살해했지
Theon Greyjoy murdered
both his brothers.
즉, 산사 스타크가
윈터펠의 후계자다
That makes Sansa Stark
the heir to Winterfell.
난 그 애를 티렐에게
넘겨줄 생각 없다
And I am not about to hand
her over to the Tyrells.
이 전쟁에서 티렐군의
도움을 받고 있잖습니까
The Tyrell army is
helping us to win this war.
그들을 저버리는 게
현명한 걸까요?
Do you really think
it's wise to refuse them?
뭘 저버린다는 거냐
이건 음모 아니더냐
There's nothing to refuse.
This is a plot.
음모는 공공연한 사실이 아니다
Plots are not public knowledge.
조프리의 혼인이 끝나기 전엔
And the Tyrells
won't carry this one out
티렐은 이 건을 공론화 못 해
until after Joffrey's wedding.
우리가 먼저 행동해서
이 동맹의 싹을 잘라야 한다
We need to act first and
kill this union in its crib.
어떻게요?
And how do we do that?
산사 스타크에게
다른 신랑을 찾아줘야지
We find Sansa Stark
a different husband.
- 대단하네요
- 그래, 그렇지
- Wonderful.
- Yes, it is.
진심은 아니시겠죠
You can't mean it.
왜 아니냐
I can and I do.
조프리가 그 불쌍한 애
아비 목을 벤 후 부터
Joffrey has made this
poor girl's life miserable
그 애가 그 고생을 했는데
since the day he took
her father's head.
이제 조프리에게 벗어나니
나한테 보낸다고요?
Now she's finally free of
him and you give her to me?
아무리 아버님이라도
너무 가혹하군요
That's cruel even for you.
그 애를 학대할 거냐?
Do you intend
on mistreating her?
그 애의 행복은
내 관심사가 아니다
The girl's happiness
is not my concern,
- 너도 그래야 할 것이야
- 아직 어린 애 아닙니까!
- nor should it be yours.
- She's a child!
월경 시작했어
전에 얘기한 적 있어
She's flowered, I assure you. She
and I have discussed it at length.
자, 봤냐? 혼인하고
잠자리 하고 임신시켜라
There, you see? You will wed her,
bed her, and put a child in her.
- 그럴 능력은 있겠지
- 싫다면요?
- Surely you're capable of that.
- And if I refuse?
전공의 상을
받고 싶다지 않았냐?
You wanted to be rewarded
for your valor in battle.
산사 스타크는 네놈이
감히 바라기도 힘든 상이다
Sansa Stark is a finer reward than
you could ever dare hope for.
넌 이미 혼인
적령기가 지났잖느냐
And it is past time
you were wed.
전 혼인 했었습니다
I was wed.
기억 못하시는 겁니까
Or don't you remember?
너무 잘 기억할 뿐이다
Only too well.
신들께 감사할 일이야
You should be
thanking the gods for this.
네 주제엔 과하지
This is more than you deserve.
티리온은 자기 몫을 할 거다
Tyrion will do as he's bid.
너도 마찬가지고
As will you.
무슨 뜻이시죠?
What do you mean?
넌 로라스 경과 혼인한다
You'll marry Ser Loras.
- 안 합니다
- 그 애는 하이가든 후계자야
- I will not.
- The boy is heir to Highgarden.
티리온은 북부를 확보하고
넌 리치를 확보한다
Tyrion will secure the North,
you will secure the Reach.
- 안 합니다
- 할 거야
- No, I won't do it.
- Yes, you will.
아직 가임기니
재혼해서 애를 낳아야지
You're still fertile. You need
to marry again and breed.
전 왕비 섭정이지
씨받이가 아닙니다
I am Queen Regent,
not some broodmare.
넌 내 딸이다!
You're my daughter!
내 명령대로 해라
You will do as I command
넌 로라스 티렐과 혼인한다
and you will marry Loras Tyrell
이걸로 너에 대한 역겨운
소문을 끝내는 거다
and put an end
to the disgusting rumors
about you once and for all.
아버지, 제발 제게
또 이러지 마세요
Father, don't make me
do it again, please.
두 말 않겠다
Not another word.
자식들아
My children.
너흰 충분히
가문에 먹칠을 했어
You've disgraced the Lannister
name for far too long.
영자막: honeybunny
한글자막: PsyenceFictionist@gmail.com
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
♪ 늘 여름이라네♪
♪ It's always summer ♪
♪ 바다 속에선♪
♪ Under the sea ♪
♪ 난 알아요♪
♪ I know, I know ♪
♪ 오, 오, 오♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ 새들은 비늘이 돋혔고♪
♪ The birds have scales ♪
♪ 물고긴 날개가 있죠♪
♪ And the fish take wing ♪
♪ 난 알아요♪
♪ I know, I know ♪
♪ 오오오♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ 비는 메말랐고♪
♪ The rain is dry ♪
♪ 눈은 거꾸로 내리죠♪
♪ And snow falls up ♪
♪ 난 알아요♪
♪ I know, I know ♪
♪ 오, 오, 오♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ 돌은 갈라지고♪
♪ The stones crack open ♪
♪ 물은 불타죠♪
♪ The water burns ♪
♪ 어둠이 내려와 춤을 춰요♪
♪ The shadows come to dance ♪
♪ 임금님♪
♪ My lord ♪
♪ 어둠이 내려와♪
♪ The shadows come ♪
♪ 연주하죠♪
♪ To play ♪
♪ 어둠이 내려와 춤을 춰요♪
♪ The shadows come to dance ♪
♪ 임금님♪
♪ My lord ♪
♪ 어둠이 내려와♪
♪ The shadows come ♪
♪ 머무르죠♪
♪ To stay. ♪